Guide to the Eugene O'Neill Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1914-1970; Series III; 15.6; (42 boxes)
  - PLAYS
    - Long Day's Journey Into Night
      - Later draft
        - Typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1168-1169)
      - Invitation to dinner to mark publication, 1956 Feb 20 (Box 59, Folder 1170)
      - Financial reports for production by Leigh Connell, Theodore Mann, and José Quintero, 1956-65 (Box 59, Folder 1171-1174)
      - Poster advertising film (2 copies), n.d.
      - Contracts
        - Random House (Firm), 1955 Feb 17 (Box 59, Folder 1175)
          Two different contracts.
        - Carl Strakosch, 1956 Feb 8 (Box 59, Folder 1176)
        - S. Fischer Verlag, 1956 Mar 15 (Box 59, Folder 1177)
        - José Quintero, Theodore Mann, and Leigh Connell, 1956 Jul 11 (Box 59, Folder 1178)
        - Lars Schmidt, 1956 Jul 18 (Box 59, Folder 1179)
        - José Quintero, Theodore Mann, and Leigh Connell, 1956 Sep 19 (Box 59, Folder 1180)
      - Programs and brochures, 1955-56 (Box 59, Folder 1181-1182)
      - Programs and brochures (cont.), 1956-62, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1183-1189)
      - Clippings of reviews and advertisements, 1955-56 Jul (Box 60, Folder 1190-1195)
      - Clippings of reviews and advertisements (cont.), 1956 Aug-57 (Box 61, Folder 1196-1208)
      - Clippings of reviews and advertisements (cont.), 1958-70, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1209-1220)
    - The Long Voyage Home
      - Clipping of printed version, annotated in unidentified hand (Box 62, Folder 1221)
        Signed by Nina Moise.
      - Clippings of reviews and advertisements, 1939-61, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1222-1225)
    - "The Man on Iron Horseback"
      See: Cycle plays, box 45, folder 952
    - Marco Millions
      - Notes and drawings, holograph (Box 63, Folder 1226)
      - Early draft, holograph, in two volumes, 1923-24 (Box 63, Folder 1227-1228)
        Begun 1923 Aug 11; finished 1924 Oct
        11.
      - Later draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1229-1231)
      - Contracts
        - Theatre Guild, 1927 May 21 (Box 63, Folder 1232)
        - London Mask Theatre, Ltd., 1938 Nov 30 (Box 63, Folder 1233)
      - Programs, 1964, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1234)
      - Clippings of reviews and advertisements, 1927-64, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1235-1237)
    - A Moon for the Misbegotten
      - Notes and drawings, holograph, 1941-43 (Box 64, Folder 1238)
      - Early draft, holograph, corrected, 1943 May 17
        Note by EO: "2nd d."
      - Intermediate draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1239-1240)
        Includes holograph pages.
      - Later draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1241-1243)
        Signed by CMO, 1947.
      - Contracts
        - Carl Strakosch, 1952 Aug 29 (Box 64, Folder 1244)
        - Jonathan Cape Limited, 1952 Sep 10 (Box 64, Folder 1245)
      - Programs, 1919-69, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1246-1247)
      - Clippings of reviews and advertisements, 1947-56 (Box 64, Folder 1248-1254)
      - Clippings of reviews and advertisements (cont.), 1957-68, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1255-1259)
    - The Moon of the Caribbees
      - Clipping of printed version, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1260)
    - More Stately Mansions
      See: Cycle plays, box 45, folders 953-965
    - Mourning Becomes Electra
      - Notes on characters and story, holograph, in volume (Box 66, Folder 1261)
        Inscribed to CMO, 1930 Jan 15.
      - Notes on dialogues, holograph, in volume (Box 66, Folder 1262)
        Inscribed to CMO, 1934 Mar.
      - Dialogue, holograph and typescript carbon, corrected (Box 66, Folder 1263)
      - "Homecoming," very early draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1264-1266)
      - "The Hunted," very early draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1267-1268)
      - "The Haunted," very early draft, holograph, corrected, 1930 Feb 12 (Box 66, Folder 1269-1270)
      - "Homecoming," early draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1271-1273)
        Inscribed to CMO, 1931 Apr 23.
      - "The Hunted," early draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1274-1275)
      - "The Haunted," early draft, holograph, corrected, 1930 Jul 11 (Box 67, Folder 1276-1277)
      - "Homecoming," early intermediate draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1278-1280)
      - "The Hunted," early intermediate draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1281-1283)
      - "The Haunted," early intermediate draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1284-1286)
      - "Homecoming," early intermediate draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1287-1289)
      - "The Hunted," early intermediate draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1290-1291)
      - "The Haunted," early intermediate draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1292-1293)
      - "Homecoming," later draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1294-1296)
      - "The Hunted," later draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1297-1298)
      - "The Haunted," later draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1299-1300)
      - "Homecoming," working copy, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1301-1302)
        Inscribed to CMO, 1935 Dec 28.
      - "The Hunted," working copy, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1303)
      - "The Haunted," working copy, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1304)
      - All three plays, first galley proof, corrected, in volume, n.y. Jul 11-17 (Box 69, Folder 1305)
      - "Homecoming," second galley proof, corrected, in volume (Box 69, Folder 1306-1307)
        in, and loose notes, holograph.
      - "The Hunted," second galley proof, corrected, in volume (Box 69, Folder 1308-1309)
        in.
      - "The Haunted," second galley proof, corrected, in volume (Box 69, Folder 1310-1311)
      - "The Haunted," galley proof, n.d.
      - Production notes by Carlotta Monterey O'Neill, typescript and carbon, 1961 Aug 20 (Box 69, Folder 1312)
      - Contracts
        - Hans Bartsch, 1936 Jan 22 (Box 69, Folder 1313)
        - Albert Bonniers förlag (4 copies), 1937 Apr 19 (Box 69, Folder 1314)
          Includes Ah, Wilderness!.
        - Anmer Hall, 1937, 1938 (Box 69, Folder 1315)
        - RKO Radio Pictures, Inc., 1946, 1947 (Box 69, Folder 1316)
        - Robert Fryer, 1956 Nov 7 (Box 69, Folder 1317)
        - Tschechischem National Theatre (Prague, Czech Republic), n.d. (Box 69, Folder 1318)
      - Programs and brochures, 1931-67, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 1319-1323)
      - Clippings of reviews and advertisements, 1931-38 (Box 70, Folder 1324-1335)
      - Clippings of reviews and advertisements, 1939-67, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1336-1342)
    - Nine Plays
      - Brochure, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1343)
    - "Nothing Is Lost Save Honor"
      See: Cycle plays, box 46, folder 966
    - "The Ole Davil"
    - Recklessness
      - Draft, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1344)
    - The Rope
      - Clippings of reviews, 1955 (Box 71, Folder 1345)
    - S. S. Glencairn
      - Programs and brochures, 1924-66, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1346-1347)
      - Clippings of reviews and advertisements, 1966 (Box 71, Folder 1348)
    - Servitude
      - Clipping of review, 1960 Apr 13 (Box 71, Folder 1349)
    - Strange Interlude
      - Notes and drawings, holograph (Box 72, Folder 1350)
      - Early draft, holograph, corrected
        - Vol. I, 1927 Feb 24 (Box 72, Folder 1351-1353)
        - Vol. II, 1927 Feb 24 (Box 72, Folder 1354-1356)
        - Vol. III, 1927 Feb 24 (Box 72, Folder 1357-1359)
      - Intermediate draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1360-1362)
      - Later draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 1363-1365)
        Includes note of explanation, holograph.
      - Galley proof, corrected, n.d.
      - Legal Case Regarding Plagiarism
        See also: [Ideas, scenarios, and notes for plays], holograph, in notebook, box 77, folder 1426
        - "Page for Page Comparisons," holograph, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 1366)
        - "Eugene O'Neill's Comments on First List of Alleged Similarities. Page for Page Comparisons," typescript, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 1367)
        - Closing arguments in Georges Lewys vs. Eugene O'Neill, typescript, 1931 Mar 16 (Box 73, Folder 1368)
        - Closing arguments in Georges Lewys vs. Eugene O'Neill, typescript carbon, corrected, 1931 Mar 16 (Box 73, Folder 1369)
      - Contracts
        - Fanny R. Wallich, 1935 May 31 (Box 73, Folder 1370)
        - Petru Comarnescu, 1939 Jan 11 (Box 73, Folder 1371)
        - Loew's Incorporated, 1955 Aug 5 (Box 73, Folder 1372)
      - Programs and brochures, 1928-63, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 1373-1375)
      - Clippings of reviews and advertisements, 1928-65, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 1376-1378)
    - The Straw
      - Contract with George Crouse Tyler, 1919 Dec 15 (Box 73, Folder 1379)
      - Clippings of reviews and advertisements, 1920-38, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 1380)
    - Thirst
      - Draft, typescript carbon (2 copies), n.d. (Box 73, Folder 1381)
        Includes Richard J. Madden Play Company, Inc. binder.
    - A Touch of the Poet
      See: Cycle plays, box 46, folder 968 through box 47, folder 989
    - "The Visit of Malatesta"
      - Notes and outline, holograph, in notebook, 1940-41 (Box 74, Folder 1382)
    - Warnings
      - Draft, typescript carbon (2 copies), n.d. (Box 74, Folder 1383)
    - The Web
      - Draft, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 1384)
    - Welded
      - Contracts
        - Arch Selwyn, 1924 Feb 4 (Box 74, Folder 1385)
        - Cai Ingersley Nielsen, 1948 Apr 13 (Box 74, Folder 1386)
      - Clipping of review, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 1387)
    - Where the Cross Is Made
      - Program, 1939 (Box 74, Folder 1388)
      - Clipping of review, 1920 Jun 9 (Box 74, Folder 1389)
  - POEMS
    - "Ballad of the Seamy Side," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 1390)
    - [Dirty bricks of buildings...], typescript, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 1391)
      On Tao House stationery.
    - "Eyes"
      - Typescript, 1917 (Box 75, Folder 1392)
      - Typescript, corrected, on Tao House (Danville, Calif.) stationery, n.d.
      - Manuscript, in Carlotta Monterey O'Neill's hand
    - "Fragment Suggested by Newspaper Article," holograph, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 1393)
    - "Fragments", 1942 (Box 75, Folder 1394-1395)
      Drafts, holograph, corrected
      typescript, corrected; and typescript
      carbon. Includes copies in CMO's
      hand. Includes two envelopes.
    - "Free," typescript, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 1396)
    - "The Ghost," holograph, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 1397)
      Annotated by CMO: "Eugene O'Neill -
      year (?)."
    - "Good Night," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 1398)
      Includes typescript, corrected, on
      Tao House stationery, annotated by
      EO: "Hell Hole - 1916."
    - [I had dwelt too long in lives...], typescript, corrected, 1915 (Box 75, Folder 1399)
    - [In that last hour...], typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 1400)
      On Tao House stationery. Annotated by
      EO: "Hell Hole - 1915."
    - "Moonlight," typescript, 1916 (Box 75, Folder 1401)
    - "Quiet Song in Time of Chaos", 1940 Dec 28 (Box 75, Folder 1402)
      "To Carlotta on Her Birthday."
      Six copies: one holograph; three
      typescript, corrected; two
      typescript. Two envelopes.
    - "Revolution," holograph, corrected, 1916 (Box 75, Folder 1403)
    - "Silence"
      - Holograph, corrected, 1916 Jul 9 (Box 75, Folder 1404)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d.
    - "Song in Chaos", 1942 Dec 28 (Box 75, Folder 1405)
      Five copies: one holograph (includes
      envelope); two typescript, corrected
      one typescript; one typescript
      carbon.
    - "A Song of Moods"
      - Typescript, corrected, 1914 (Box 75, Folder 1406)
      - Typescript, n.d.
      - Manuscript, in Carlotta Monterey O'Neill's hand
    - "The Stars"
      - Typescript, corrected, 1915 (Box 75, Folder 1407)
      - Typescript, corrected, on Tao House (Danville, Calif.) stationery, n.d.
    - "'Tis of Thee," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 1408)
      On Tao House stationery, annotated by
      EO: "Hell Hole - 1917."
    - [What do you see...]
      - Holograph, corrected, 1915 (Box 75, Folder 1409)
      - Typescript, corrected, on Tao House (Danville, Calif.) stationery, n.d.
    - "The White Night," typescript, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 1410)
    - Unidentified fragment, holograph, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 1411)
  - OTHER WRITINGS
    - The American Spectator. Vol. I, No. 4; Vol. I, No. 5; Vol. I, No. 7; Vol. I, No. 8, 1933 Feb-Jun
    - "From Alice in Baccilland," holograph (Box 76, Folder 1412)
    - [Maksim Gorky], holograph, [1936] (Box 76, Folder 1413)
      On Casa Genotta stationery.
    - Inscriptions: Eugene O'Neill to Carlotta Monterey O'Neill
      - Transcriptions in Carlotta Monterey O'Neill's hand, in notebook (Box 76, Folder 1414)
        Includes copies of photographs.
      - Two envelopes (titles in Carlotta Monterey O'Neill's hand) that housed inscriptions
    - "Last Will and Testament of Silverdene Emblem O'Neill"
      - Early draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 76, Folder 1415)
        Annotated in CMO's hand: "1940 Dec
        17."
      - Later draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 76, Folder 1416)
      - Copies (eight) made after Eugene O'Neill's death, typescript and carbon, 1955, n.d. (Box 76, Folder 1417)
        Two copies signed by CMO, one
        inscribed to Eugene Davidson, 1955
        Oct 3.
    - [Nobel Prize acceptance speech], draft, holograph and typescript, corrected, [1936] (Box 76, Folder 1418)
    - "O'Neill on Strindberg," clipping of printed version, The New York Times, 1924 Jan 6 (Box 76, Folder 1419)
    - "Professor G. P. Baker," clipping of printed version, The New York Times, 1935 Jan 13 (Box 76, Folder 1420)
    - "Tributes to George Pierce Baker by Eugene O'Neill and Lee Simonson," printed version, The Emerson Quarterly (2 copies), 1935 Jan (Box 76, Folder 1421)
  - NOTES
    - [Books by others], holograph, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 1422)
    - "Cycles," holograph, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 1423)
      Chronicles O'Neill's life and work,
      1888-1946.
    - [Don Juan of Austria and Phillip II], holograph (Box 77, Folder 1424)
    - [Ideas for plays], holograph, in notebook, [1918-20] (Box 77, Folder 1425)
      Includes notes on Chris Christopherson.
    - [Ideas, scenarios, and notes for plays], holograph, in notebook, [1920s-30s] (Box 77, Folder 1426)
      holograph. Also includes material
      regarding Strange Interlude legal
      case.
    - "Ideas for Possible Future Plays," holograph, in notebook, 1934-38 (Box 77, Folder 1427)
    - [Ideas for plays], holograph, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 1428)
    - "List of all plays ever written by me, including those I later destroyed, giving where and when they were written," holograph, in notebook (Box 77, Folder 1429)
      Lists plays, 1913-37.
    - "Negro Play," holograph, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 1430)
    - Nietzsche quotations, holograph, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 1431)
    - [Notes on plots and characters], holograph, in volume, 1932-35
      See: Cycle plays, box 141, folder 2507
    - "Notes - Principally Concerning Masks (From a Notebook)," holograph, typescript, and typescript carbon, corrected (Box 77, Folder 1432)
    - "Play about Aeschylus," holograph, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 1433)
    - "Robespierre," holograph, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 1434)
    - [Shih Huang-Ti], holograph, in notebook, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 1435)
      Includes one loose page.
    - "Time Wearily Coiling," holograph note, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 1436)
  - WORK DIARIES
    - Work diary, holograph, in volume, 1924-28 (Box 78, Folder 1437)
    - Work diary, holograph, in volume, 1929-33 (Box 78, Folder 1438)
      Inscribed by CMO, 1931 Sep.
    - Work diary, holograph, in volume, 1934-38 (Box 78, Folder 1439)
    - Work diary, holograph, in volume, 1939-43 (Box 78, Folder 1440)
  - WRITINGS OF OTHERS
    - Bowen, Croswell. "Eugene O'Neill's Magic Mountain," typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 1441)
      Assisted by Shane Rudraighe O'Neill.
    - Cane, Melville
      - "I Remember Distinctly," poem, holograph, 1946 Mar 2 (Box 79, Folder 1442)
      - "A Song for Linda," poem, typescript, 1947 Sep 8
        Sent to CMO.
    - Clark, Barrett Harper
      - "Aeschylus and O'Neill," printed version, 1932 Nov (Box 79, Folder 1443)
        Annotated: "With regards from BHC."
      - [Eugene O'Neill], typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 1444)
        Annotated: "For the London Arts
        Gazette."
    - Davidson, Eugene
      - [Review of Long Day's Journey Into Night ], typescript, corrected, signed, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 1445)
      - [Review of A Touch of the Poet ], typescript carbon, signed, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 1446)
    - Dowson, Ernest Christopher. [Impenitentia ultima], in Eugene O'Neill's hand (Box 79, Folder 1447)
    - Hsiao, Chi'en. "Chinese Writers' Dilemma," clipping of printed version, The Listener, 1942 Jun 18 (Box 79, Folder 1448)
    - Jones, Robert Edmond. "The Drama of the Future," typescript, corrected, 1942 Dec 12 (Box 79, Folder 1449)
      Noted on cover: "Delivered at the
      Metropolitan Museum at the Drama
      Symposium, Jan. 21, 1943."
    - Josephson, Lennart Hjalmar. [Notes on Eugene O'Neill's cycle plays taken from EO's work diary], holograph, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 1450)
    - Kapp, David. "Judgement Day," poem, typescript, signed, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 1451)
    - Kozol, Harry L. "The Psychopath Before the Law," printed version, New England Journal of Medicine, 1959 Mar 26 (Box 79, Folder 1452)
      Inscribed to CMO, 1959 Jul 17.
      Includes mailing envelope.
    - Langner, Lawrence. "O'Neill and Strange Interlude " and "O'Neill and The Iceman Cometh ," printed version, annotated by Carlotta Monterey O'Neill, [1951] (Box 79, Folder 1453)
      From The Magic Curtain: The Story of a Life in Two Fields, Theatre and Invention, By the Founder of the Theatre Guild (New York: Dutton,
      1951), p. 228-287 and p. 397-480.
    - Levy, Martin David. "Mourning Becomes Electra (Opera Treatment, in Four Acts)," typescript carbon (Box 79, Folder 1454)
    - Mana-Zucca. "The Golden Rule," printed musical score, 1946 (Box 79, Folder 1455)
      Inscribed to EO. Includes two drafts,
      holograph, of "Rap, Rap, Rap Song"
      and "Potato Song."
    - Middleton, George. "The Dramatists Guild: What It Is and Does...How It Happened and Why...," printed version, 1959 Jun (Box 79, Folder 1456)
    - Miller, Jordan Yale. "A Critical Bibliography of Eugene O'Neill," typescript carbon, [1956?] (Box 79, Folder 1457-1467)
    - Molina-Tellez, Félix. "Un tema de nuestra época," printed version, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 1468)
      Inscribed to EO in Spanish, 1937.
    - Nathan, George Jean. "Eugene O'Neill," printed version, annotated by Carlotta Monterey O'Neill, [1952] (Box 80, Folder 1469)
      From The World of George Jean Nathan (New York: Knopf, 1952), p.
      30-43.
    - O'Neill, Eugene, Jr.
      - "The Attic Pattern," clipping of printed version, The New York Times Book Review, 1945 Jan 28 (Box 80, Folder 1470)
        Review of Paideia: The Ideals of Greek Culture by Werner Jaeger.
      - "Down Pindar's 'Impetuous, Dithyrambic Tide,'" clipping of printed version, The New York Times Book Review, 1947 Apr 6 (Box 80, Folder 1471)
        Review of The Odes of Pindar translated by Richmond Lattimore.
      - "England's Golden Age," clipping of printed version, The New York Times Book Review, 1947 Apr 20 (Box 80, Folder 1472)
        Review of The Portable Elizabethan Reader edited by Hiram Haydn.
      - "Famous Voyage, Cut-Rate," clipping of printed version, The New York Times Book Review, 1946 Dec 8 (Box 80, Folder 1473)
        Review of Homer's Odyssey translated by E. V. Rieu.
      - "Finest Intellect of Antiquity," clipping of printed version, The Saturday Review of Literature, 1946 Dec 21 (Box 80, Folder 1474)
        Review of The Politics of Aristotle translated by Ernest
        Barker.
      - Fitts, Dudley and Robert Fitzgerald, trans. The Antigone of Sophocles. Review of, printed version, American Journal of Philology, 1939 Oct (Box 80, Folder 1475)
        Inscribed to EO and CMO.
      - "Homeric Hexameters," clipping of printed version, The New York Times Book Review, 1944 Nov 5 (Box 80, Folder 1476)
        Review of William Benjamin Smith
        and Walter Miller's translation of
        Homer's Iliad.
      - "The Importance of Final Syllables in Greek Verse," printed version, Transactions of the American Philological Association, 1939 (Box 80, Folder 1477)
      - "The Localization of Metrical Word-Types in the Greek Hexameter: Homer, Hesiod, and the Alexandrians," printed version, Yale Classical Studies, 1942 (Box 80, Folder 1478)
      - "Note on Phrynichus' Phoenissae and Aeschylus' Persae, printed version, Classical Philology, 1942 Oct (Box 80, Folder 1479)
      - Page, Denys Lionel. Euripides. Medea. Review of, printed version, American Journal of Philology, 1939 Oct (Box 80, Folder 1480)
      - "The Prologue of the Troades of Euripides," printed version, Transactions of the American Philological Association, 1941 (Box 80, Folder 1481)
      - Schütze, Kurt. Beiträge zum Verständnis der Phainomena Arats. Review of, printed version, Gnomon, 1938 Mar (Box 80, Folder 1482)
      - "Values From Above," clipping of printed version, The New York Times Book Review, 1945 Feb 25 (Box 80, Folder 1483)
        Review of Plato and Modern Education by Richard Livingstone.
      - Wifstrand, Albert. Von Kallimachos zu Nonnos, metrischstilistiche Untersuchungen zur späteren griechischen Epik und zu verwandten Gedichtgattungen. Review of, printed version, American Journal of Philology, 1936 Jul (Box 80, Folder 1484)
        Inscribed to EO.
      - "Word-Accents and Final Syllables in Latin Verse," printed version, Transactions of the American Philological Association, 1940 (Box 80, Folder 1485)
    - Shaw, Patricia Joudry. "Longer is the Journey Through the Night: A Drama in Three Acts Written Posthumously by Eugene O'Neill and Transmitted in Automatic Writing Through the Hand of a Spiritualistic Medium," typescript mimeograph, 1961 (Box 80, Folder 1486)
      Includes letter from Shaw to CMO,
      1962 Jan 16.
    - Sheaffer, Louis
      - "The Question Is, Where's Off Broadway Going?," typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 1487)
      - [Review of Desire Under the Elms at Circle in the Square, staged by José Quintero], typescript carbon, corrected (Box 80, Folder 1488)
    - Weinberger, Harry. "Sale of Private Letters," typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 1489)
    - Unidentified. "Eugene O'Neill's A Touch of the Poet: The Hague Company's Impressive Performance," drafts, typescript and carbon (Box 80, Folder 1490)
      Initials: "B. S."
- Personal Papers, 1872-1970; Series IV; 9.8; (27 boxes)
  Series IV, Personal Papers, is organized into eight
  subseries: Address Books, Carlotta Monterey O'Neill
  Diaries and Calendars, Certificates and Awards, Clippings
  and Ephemera, Financial and Legal Material, Inscriptions
  and Signatures, Medical Information, and Personal
  Writings and Notes.
  - ADDRESS BOOKS
    - "Addresses," brown volume, n.d. (Box 81, Folder 1491)
      Signed by CMO, 1936.
    - "Addresses," black volume, n.d. (Box 81, Folder 1492)
      Signed by CMO, 1952 Jul 2.
    - "Telephone," small black ringbinder (Box 81, Folder 1493)
    - "Telephone," large black ringbinder (Box 81, Folder 1494)
    - "Telephone," large brown ringbinder (Box 82, Folder 1495)
  - CARLOTTA MONTEREY O'NEILL DIARIES AND CALENDARS
    Arranged chronologically.
    - Green "Daily Reminder"
      O'Neill bookplate.
      For lists of photographs pasted in, see: Appendix
      - Diary, 1928 (Box 83, Folder 1496)